Wrege, Charles D. Research Audio-Visual Materials 6395 AV
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Research Audio-Visual Materials
1925-2014
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6395 AV
9.33 cubic feet
9.3 linear ft.
Audio cassette tapes, audio open-reel tapes, video cassettes, DVDs.
8691784
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 24, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 11, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
8691784
- Hawthorne Works Museum - cicero, IL -- August 7, 2009 (Box 1)
- Hawthorne Scrapbook (Box 2)
  Scope and Contents
  Cover, TOC, 1-28
- Reels 5 to 7 (Box 3)
- Reels 5 to 7 (Box 4)
- 1925 Hawthorne Pics 1-28 (Box 5)
- Hawthorne 1-4 Reel; Hawthorne 5-7 Reel - 4/6/2014 (Box 6)
- Hawthorne Study - reels 5-7 (Box 7)
- Chuck Wrege "The Story of the Hawthorne Studies"; video by Mitch Dakelman; Friday, October 28, 2011 (Box 8)
  disc one of three
- Chuck Wrege "The Story of the Hawthorne Studies"; video by Mitvh Dakelman - Friday, October 28, 2011 (Box 9)
  Disc three of three
- Chuck Wrege "The Story of the Hawthorne Studies"; video by Mitch Dakelman - Friday, October 28, 2011 (Box 10)
  disc two of three
- Report from Hawthorne: The Year They Discovered People - Hawthorne Film (Box 11)
- The Search for the film "Hawthorne" / PowerPoint Dr. Charles D. Wrege; July 15, 2007 (Box 12)
- Hawthorne - 1975 Interviews (Box 13)
- Western Electric - 1924 Hawthorne works (Box 14)
- Western Electric 1927 - Relay Test Room (Box 15)
- Western Electric - Voices in paper (Box 16)
- Western Electrician - March, 1904 on Lorimer Automatic Telephone System (Box 17)
- Western Electrician - March 1904. Photos of Lorimer Brothers Automatic Telephone System (Box 18)
- Route der Industriekult (Box 19)
- Faszination Ruhrgebiet Industriekultur (Box 20)
- Breitbart's Hawthorne Recreation circa 1987, 2007 (Box 21)
- Eric Breitbart - 2007 - "The Last Pin Factory" (Box 22)
- Management History According to Chuck Wrege - 50 Years of Research -- Raw footage (Box 23)
- Management History by Chuck Wrege - 50 Years of Research (Box 24)
- A Miracle for Mrs. Smith (Box 25)
  dubbed 10/03/2006
- A Miracle for Mrs. Smith (Box 26)
- Short Cuts to Quantity, 1923 (Box 27)
- Short cuts to quantity, 1923 (Box 28)
- Frank Gilbreth Film (Box 29)
- Gilbreth's Films Ball Brothers Mason Jars (Box 30)
- Gilbreth's Films Odds and Ends #2 (Box 31)
- Gilbreth's Films Odds and Ends #3 (Box 32)
- World's Telephone Workshop, 1923 (Box 33)
- Classic Telephone History Films - Volume 1 (Box 34)
  2 DVD set
- Classic Telephone History Films - Volume 2 (Box 35)
- Management History according to Chuck Wrege (Box 36)
- Management History according to Chuck Wrege (Box 37)
- Chuck Wrege's Career - April 1, 2012 / video by Mitchell Dakelman (Box 38)
  Disc one of two
- Chuck Wrege's Career - April 1, 2012 / video by Mitchell Dakelman (Box 39)
  Disc two of two
- The Phantom of the Operator (Box 40)
- The Phantom of the Operator (Box 41)
- Midvale Steel - NCM - Wrege (Box 42)
- C.D. Wrege - Midvale Steel & Management History Photographs (Box 43)
- Steel Photos (Box 44)
  Midvale Steel; Blacksmith shop; hand rolling mill; etc.
- The Last Pin Factory (Box 45)
- Cinepingle a/k/a The Last Pin Factory, 2008 (Box 46)
- Wrege - 3512 (Box 47)
- RAF Signals Museum - RAF Henlow - Relay Room Simulation (Box 48)
- Search for the Insignificant 2004 (Box 49)
- Conference on Harvard University, Business School (Box 50)
- RG4592MI - Delco Farm Lighting 1918 Film (Box 51)
- The Voice from the Screen - 1925 (Box 52)
- Cycle of Service Steel: Symphony of an Industry; Making & Shaping of Steel (Box 53)
- Greenwood, Wanda Interview - 199814/26 (Box 54)
- WUSTE Archives - New Birney (Box 55)
- Panel Mechanical "Mrckine-Switching"; Manvel 1939 (Box 56)
- PAL Format (Box 57)
- Chuck Wrege's War Years -- 1943-1946 -- Video April 1, 2012 (Box 58)
- Chuck Wrege's War Years -- 1943-1946 -- Video April 1, 2012 (Box 58)
- The Official Records of the American Civil War (Box 59)
- RCA Victor 1932 Prom film, 1 (Box 60)
- Western Electric Films, 2 (Box 60)
- The Voice from the screen and selected vitaphone shorts, 1925; 3 (Box 60)
- Wrege - Greenwood - Wanda April 26, 1985, 4 (Box 60)
- Dr. Charles Wrege. PBS Interview -- Tape #1 -- April 25, 1998, 5 (Box 60)
  duplicate of 6118 AV, 320A
- PBS Interview -- (For 'Stopwatch' Show) - 4/25/1998, 6 (Box 60)
- PBS Interview (For 'Stopwatch' Show) - tape 2 of 2, 7 (Box 60)
- Management History Research: An Interview with Chuck Wrege, 8 (Box 60)
- Stopwatch, 9 (Box 60)
- Management History Research / Dr. Charles Wrege, 10 (Box 60)
- "The Gospel According to St. Fredrick": The Shared Beliefs of F.W. Taylor and Scudder Klyce, 11 (Box 60)
- Frank Gilbreth Films, 12 (Box 60)
- Management and the worker / Dr. Chuck Wrege, 13 (Box 60)
- Gilbreth Films, 14 (Box 60)
- Clockwork / Eric Breitbart film on F.W. Taylor, 15 (Box 60)
- Interview of C.D. Wrege - tape #2 -- 4/1998, 16 (Box 60)
- Management History Tape - 3/1995, 17 (Box 60)
- Harvard University - Presentation to Academy of Management Meeting - Aug. 1983, 18 (Box 60)
- Gilbreath - (No Sound), 19 (Box 60)
- Hawthorne (1921), 20 (Box 60)
- Western Electric Operating Flexibility, 21 (Box 60)
- Levinson - Hawthorne Conference - 11/12/1974, 22 (Box 60)
  tape 8A and tape 8B
- BARTH - 11/8/1966, 23 (Box 60)
- Tape of J. Christian - BARTH - 3/10/1966 on Scientific Management --- (1/9/1987; C.D. Wrege), 24 (Box 60)
- J.C. BARTH Tape -- 3/10/1966, 25 (Box 60)
- On Modular Scheduling - 2/13/1969, 1 (Box 61)
  Moldy
- Synetics Class, 1972; 2 (Box 61)
  Tape is twisted, folded and MOLDY
- Data on Personality, 3 (Box 61)
- The Prisoner TV Show tape, 4 (Box 61)
- Re-Recording for Cornell of Morris L. Coolo interview - 1959 - by C.D. Wrege - 3/20/2007, 5 (Box 61)
- NY Times Interview - 6/22/1976, 6 (Box 61)
- Peter James Company/Trenton; Morris Cooke-2/12/68 // J.C. Barth-2/12/68; Not labelled, 1968; 7 (Box 61)
  3 tapes in box - they were loose and not housed, they are all moldy and brittle
- 1996 Boxes to Cornell; Side 2 of "Prisoner" 2nd show; "Prisoner" tape, 8 (Box 61)
  3 tapes in box, they were not housed when received, they are dirty, moldy and brittle
- Synetics Class-Spring 1969; Problem Solving Source on Computers; M.L. Cooke Tape, 9 (Box 61)
  3 tapes in box, they were not housed before this, the tapes are dirty, moldy and brittle
- Received from William Biddle is only labelling, 10 (Box 61)
  Tape is moldy and dirty
- John Stelling Papers -- Taylor Papers, 11 (Box 61)
  Tape is moldy and dirty and brittle
- Synetics; Synetics-10/27/1967; Synetics-2nd session, 12 (Box 61)
  3 tapes in box, they were not housed when received - all tapes are brittle, dirty and moldy
- Unlabeled, 13 (Box 61)
- Unlabeled, 14 (Box 61)
- March 3, 1984 - G. Sirchio - Interview (Box 62)
- Luther Gulick - May, 1977 - Hartford (Box 63)
- Unlabeled (Box 64)
- Hadea - (side 4) (Box 65)
- Spring Lake Beach (Box 66)
- Hudson River Line tape -- 3/12/1990 (Box 67)
- Breitbart Tape (Box 68)